<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Complete | T&#39;kara Mullins</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/complete/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/complete/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Complete</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Complete</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/complete/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Autonomy Teaming and Cognition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/arl_cog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/arl_cog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this study, Dr. Fiore and I took a new approach to how we evaluate autonomous technology in team settings. While most assessments focus solely on workload reduction, we investigated the relationship between cognitive demands and collective performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We partnered with the U.S. Army at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arl.devcom.army.mil/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DEVCOM Research Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; to study 28 military personnel during simulated combat missions, complete with a high-visual fidelity simulated environment, manned combat vehicles with real user interfaces (steering wheel, pedals, buttons, etc) and robotic combat vehicles. They completed missions both with and without an automated decision support system that provided task-switching cues and flexible task allocation capabilities to assist team coordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes our approach distinctive is the focus on cognitive efficiency. We measure whether performance gains justified the mental demands imposed by the technology. Instead of treating workload reduction as the primary goal, we examined how resources invested by team members translated into mission outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results revealed something fascinating. Teams using the autonomous support achieved higher cognitive efficiency scores, indicating better performance relative to their mental workload. However, these benefits weren&amp;rsquo;t uniform—they varied significantly between different roles and groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps most revealing was what happened to team communication. With autonomous support, teams engaged in more thoughtful, insight-driven conversations and maintained a more positive emotional tone. This suggests the technology freed cognitive resources that team members redirected toward higher-level coordination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research opens new possibilities for designing and evaluating autonomous systems. By considering both workload and performance in relation to each other, we can create technology that truly enhances &lt;strong&gt;collective capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; rather than simply reducing individual burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was accepted for publication at AHFE and will be available online in July 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Autonomy Teaming and Trust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/arl_trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/arl_trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While previous research typically treats team communication and trust in automation as separate factors that each positively impact performance, we wanted to understand how these crucial factors interact in complex operational environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with the U.S. Army&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://arl.devcom.army.mil/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DEVCOM Research Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, we tracked how soldiers communicated during simulated combat missions while operating alongside autonomous systems. The unique longitudinal design allowed us to follow the same team through multiple missions, capturing how their communication patterns evolved in relation to their trust towards the autonomous systems they used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results revealed something fascinating and counterintuitive. Team members who reported lower trust in automation spoke significantly more than those with higher trust. This effect remained even when controlling for factors like team trust, workload, role, and mission performance. This pattern challenges conventional wisdom that both increased communication and higher trust in automation independently lead to better team outcomes. While this reduced communication might reflect efficiency, it could also indicate subtle changes in team dynamics that deserve closer attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research opens new questions about how trust shapes team processes and how we should design and evaluate autonomous systems that truly enhance rather than disrupt effective team dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was accepted for publication at HFES in 2024 and was nominated for the prestigious Alphonse Chapanis best paper award. It is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/10711813241262991?icid=int.sj-abstract.citing-articles.33&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdependent Privacy on TikTok</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/tiktok/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/tiktok/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-indent: 2em;&#34;&gt; This project looked into how people share hidden, stigmatized aspects of themselves and others on social media platforms. These concealable stigmatized identities (CSIs) are increasingly being revealed online, but we know surprisingly little about what this content looks like or how others respond to it—especially when comparing self-disclosure versus disclosing someone else&#39;s identity, or when dealing with conditions that carry different levels of social stigma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tackle these questions, we collected a dataset with 2,042 TikTok videos and their 111,705 comments from popular mental health hashtags (#clinicaldepression, #depression, and #schizophrenia). We manually coded each video for disclosure types while using natural language processing to analyze comment sentiment, then built mixed-effects regression models to uncover key patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings revealed some fascinating dynamics. People were much more likely to disclose their own CSI when posting under less stigmatized hashtags (like #depression) compared to more stigmatized ones (like #schizophrenia). Conversely, when videos appeared under more stigmatized hashtags, they were more likely to contain disclosures about other people&amp;rsquo;s conditions rather than self-disclosures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also discovered a &amp;ldquo;contagion effect&amp;rdquo; in the comments. If an original video disclosed someone else&amp;rsquo;s CSI, commenters were more likely to follow suit by revealing others&amp;rsquo; conditions too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feedback patterns were equally revealing. While mental health content generally received positive responses, videos containing any form of disclosure got significantly more positive feedback than those without disclosures. However, there&amp;rsquo;s an important distinction: posts where people revealed their own CSIs received more positive feedback than those disclosing someone else&amp;rsquo;s condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work has important implications for understanding privacy boundaries in social media spaces, especially regarding sensitive health information that affects multiple people. We&amp;rsquo;re exploring what these findings mean for both individual disclosure decisions and the broader landscape of &amp;ldquo;interdependent privacy&amp;rdquo; in digital spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was accepted to computer supported cooperative work (CSCW) and will be available online in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
