<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | T&#39;kara Mullins</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu_645fa481986063ef.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASIST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/asist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/asist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    These recurrence plots show how patterns of coordination unfolded differently over time for two participants.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is currently under review for publication and we are hoping to share it in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more about entropy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coordination in Esports</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/pandas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    Image generated with ChatGPT 2025.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular competitive games are team-based, where winning depends on combining individual skill with collective decision-making. While esports has grown into a global phenomenon with major prize pools and huge audiences, we still don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand the science behind successful teamwork in this space. What makes a successful esports team? Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t a team of experts make an expert team? I think the difference is in how these teams coordinate - or work together to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tackle this question, I&amp;rsquo;m applying established team science frameworks to examine how coordination works in esports. This approach helps connect team composition and structure to processes like communication and shared understanding, and ultimately to performance outcomes. I&amp;rsquo;m specifically interested in how teams function as units. By studying coordination mechanisms—how teams communicate, synchronize, and adapt during matches—I hope to identify patterns that distinguish successful teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project, I plan to collect multiple streams of real-time data—including physiological measures, game logs, behavioral observations, and team communications—to monitor coordination as it happens. I&amp;rsquo;m partnering with digital twin faculty to develop systems that can process these diverse data streams simultaneously and detect anomalies that might signal coordination breakdowns or teamwork issues. This multi-method approach should give us unprecedented insight into the moment-by-moment dynamics of team performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to bridge theory and practice, potentially developing ways to recognize coordination patterns and improve coaching approaches. This work could help us understand what separates championship teams from the rest, with implications that might extend beyond esports to other fields where teamwork matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is just getting started so check back in or reach out for updates!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more about studying esports?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human-Autonomy Teaming</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/pytorch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    These recurrence plots show how patterns of coordination unfolded differently over time for two participants.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-indent: 2em;&#34;&gt; Team environments increasingly integrate autonomous technologies to reduce workload and enhance performance. However, traditional metrics may overlook indirect benefits, particularly cognitive efficiency—the balance between workload and performance. This study examined how autonomous decision support systems (ADSS) affected cognitive efficiency and team communication in a high-fidelity simulated combat environment. Twenty-eight military personnel completed ten missions, alternating between conditions with and without ADSS that provided task-switching cues and flexible task allocation. Results showed that missions using ADSS produced higher cognitive efficiency, indicating improved performance relative to workload, though benefits varied by role and team. Teams also demonstrated enhanced communication patterns with ADSS, using more insight-related language, and maintaining a more positive tone. These findings highlight cognitive efficiency as a valuable metric for evaluating autonomy in complex environments and reveal how autonomous systems can enhance team effectiveness through improved team processes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was accepted for publication at AHFE and will be available online in July 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-indent: 2em;&#34;&gt; Trust in automation and team communication are crucial factors in human-agent teaming. While research has examined how trust in automation and team dynamics impact performance separately, less is known about how they combine to influence team dynamics. This study investigated how team speech dynamics are related to trust in automation, team perceptions, and workload in the context of a longitudinal multi-participant computer simulated military mission using active-duty military personnel. Results showed that participants with lower trust in automation spoke more than their teammates with higher trust in automation, even after controlling for perceptions of team trust, cooperation, workload, role on the team, and team performance. A common finding in the team literature is that more team communication and more trust in automation are, separately, better for team performance. Thus, this research is an initial step toward demonstrating how automation alters the team dynamics typically considered essential to their success. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was accepted for publication at HFES in 2024. It is available here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more these studies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated, Confined, and Extreme Teams- LUNAres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/lunares/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/lunares/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    These recurrence plots show how patterns of coordination unfolded differently over time for two participants.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project, I partnered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andres-k%C3%A4osaar-322760b5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andres Käosaar&lt;/a&gt; to investigate how coordinated responses to challenges impacted stress for crew-members on a space analog mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is in pre-print for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ingroup.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;INGRoup 2025&lt;/a&gt;! We will share the full print soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more about entropy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated, Confined, and Extreme Teams- SampEn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/scikit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/scikit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    These recurrence plots show how patterns of coordination unfolded differently over time for two participants.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project, I partnered with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/andres-k%C3%A4osaar-322760b5/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andres Käosaar&lt;/a&gt; to explore how astronaut teams function under extreme conditions, specifically focusing on the emotional patterns that emerge during space missions and simulated space environments. This work addresses a critical challenge for future Mars missions, where NASA will rely on teams operating in isolated, confined, and extreme (ICE) conditions for extended periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While emotions clearly impact team performance, decision-making, creativity, and overall effectiveness, the tools we&amp;rsquo;ve been using to study them (particularly in ICE environments) have significant limitations. Traditional approaches to monitoring teamwork issues typically depend on self-reported surveys or ambiguous physiological markers, which often miss the dynamic nature of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s where nonlinear dyanamical systems theory comes in. We&amp;rsquo;ve applied Sample Entropy (SampEn), a technique that quantifies how predictable emotional patterns are over time. Unlike conventional methods that reduce complex emotional data to simple averages, SampEn preserves the natural fluctuations and temporal complexity of how feelings evolve within teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our dataset is particularly robust. We collected emotional expression data from journal entries and communication recordings across four different space analog environments. This diversity allows us to draw more generalizable conclusions about how emotions function in extreme settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study explores a fascinating tension: on one hand, more complex emotional patterns might indicate healthier team functioning, as adaptive systems typically show natural variability rather than rigid patterns. On the other hand, &amp;ldquo;psychological hibernation&amp;rdquo; (a flattening of emotional expression) might actually be beneficial in ICE environments specifically, serving as a coping mechanism for prolonged isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research represents the first application of SampEn to analyze emotional states in ICE teams, offering a more ecologically valid picture of how team members&amp;rsquo; feelings unfold and impact their collective functioning. By capturing these nonlinear dynamics, we&amp;rsquo;re revealing patterns that traditional analyses would likely miss—potentially transforming how we monitor and support astronaut teams on future missions to the Moon and Mars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is still in progress, but we’re excited to share more soon—we’re aiming to submit the full paper in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more about entropy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jRQA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/jrqa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/jrqa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    These recurrence plots show how patterns of coordination unfolded differently over time for two participants.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-indent: 2em;&#34;&gt; My research explores how teams function as complex adaptive systems—meaning they’re made up of many interconnected parts that interact and evolve over time. One of the biggest challenges in this work is figuring out how to represent a team. Some researchers focus on individual members and how their behaviors influence the group, while others model the team as a single unit to study how it functions as a whole. Each approach has its strengths and trade-offs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of choosing the right modeling technique, my team is especially interested in working with large, complex datasets. For example, in one project, we collected heart rate, posture, activity, and log file data at 32 samples per second over one hour from 14 participants. That’s &lt;strong&gt;8,064,000 data points&lt;/strong&gt; per session! And because we ran this twice a day for ten days, we ended up with over &lt;strong&gt;161 million data points&lt;/strong&gt; in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with this kind of data is no small task. It comes from many people, sensors, and systems—and it&amp;rsquo;s often messy or incomplete. Traditional methods usually require lots of cleaning and reshaping before you can even start analyzing. To tackle this, I partnered with Aaron Necaise and &lt;a href=&#34;https://luddy.indiana.edu/contact/profile/index.html?Mary~Jean_Amon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Mary Jean Amon&lt;/a&gt; to develop a more flexible approach to &lt;strong&gt;joint recurrence quantification analysis&lt;/strong&gt;, or jRQA, that handles imperfect data with fewer assumptions. jRQA is a technique for detecting shared patterns across time in multiple time series, revealing how systems evolve together. You can see an example of traditional RQA in the image above. Our new method starts by analyzing each team member on their own and then looks at how their behavior relates to others over time—drawing on both individual and team-level modeling strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes it easier to uncover complex team dynamics, even when people are playing different roles or interacting in very different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is still in progress, but we’re excited to share more soon—we’re aiming to submit the full paper in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more about jRQA?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MINERVA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/minerva/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/minerva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    These recurrence plots show how patterns of coordination unfolded differently over time for two participants.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this project,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently collecting data for this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more about entropy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stigmatized Identities Online</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/tiktok/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/tiktok/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;text-align: center; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rqa_example.png&#34; alt=&#34;RQA Example&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5em; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
    These recurrence plots show how patterns of coordination unfolded differently over time for two participants.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-indent: 2em;&#34;&gt; This project looked into how people share hidden, stigmatized aspects of themselves and others on social media platforms. These concealable stigmatized identities (CSIs) are increasingly being revealed online, but we know surprisingly little about what this content looks like or how others respond to it—especially when comparing self-disclosure versus disclosing someone else&#39;s identity, or when dealing with conditions that carry different levels of social stigma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To tackle these questions, we collected a dataset with 2,042 TikTok videos and their 111,705 comments from popular mental health hashtags (#clinicaldepression, #depression, and #schizophrenia). We manually coded each video for disclosure types while using natural language processing to analyze comment sentiment, then built mixed-effects regression models to uncover key patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings revealed some fascinating dynamics. People were much more likely to disclose their own CSI when posting under less stigmatized hashtags (like #depression) compared to more stigmatized ones (like #schizophrenia). Conversely, when videos appeared under more stigmatized hashtags, they were more likely to contain disclosures about other people&amp;rsquo;s conditions rather than self-disclosures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also discovered a &amp;ldquo;contagion effect&amp;rdquo; in the comments—if an original video disclosed someone else&amp;rsquo;s CSI, commenters were more likely to follow suit by revealing others&amp;rsquo; conditions too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feedback patterns were equally revealing. While mental health content generally received positive responses, videos containing any form of disclosure got significantly more positive feedback than those without disclosures. However, there&amp;rsquo;s an important distinction: posts where people revealed their own CSIs received more positive feedback than those disclosing someone else&amp;rsquo;s condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work has important implications for understanding privacy boundaries in social media spaces, especially regarding sensitive health information that affects multiple people. We&amp;rsquo;re exploring what these findings mean for both individual disclosure decisions and the broader landscape of &amp;ldquo;interdependent privacy&amp;rdquo; in digital spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was accepted to computer supported cooperative work (CSCW) and will be available online in 2025!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-top: 2em; text-align: center; font-size: 1.1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Interested in collaborating or learning more about concealable stigmatized identities?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tkara.mullin@ucf.edu&#34;&gt;Reach out via email&lt;/a&gt; or 
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tkara-mullins/&#34;&gt;connect with me on Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
